在之前的讲座中，我们谈到了运动学，特别是我们谈到了前进
In previous lectures we talked about kinematics and in particular we talked about forward
运动学。这就是问题：给定机器人的关节角度，一个是
kinematics. And that's the problem of: given the joint angles of the robot, one is the
机器人末端执行器的姿势。然后我们继续前进，我们讨论了反向运动学
pose of the robots end effector. We then moved on and we talked about inverse kinematic which
问题是：鉴于末端效应器的姿势，实现这一目标需要什么样的关节角度？
is the problem: given the end effector pose, what are the joint angles needed to achieve that?
在这个讲座中，我们将谈论速度。我们对此感兴趣
In this lecture we are going to be talking about velocities. We're interested in the
关节角度的速度与末端执行器的速度之间的关系。
relationship between the velocity of the joint angles and the velocity of the end effector.
我们对末端效应器姿势的衍生物感兴趣。
We're interested in the derivative of the end effector pose.
我们要讨论的一个主题是采用衍生产品究竟意味着什么
And one of the topics we're going to discuss is what exactly does it mean to take the derivative
机器人末端执行器的姿势。我们将简单地开始我们的讨论
of the pose of the end effector of a robot. We're going to start our discussion simply
并考虑仅在飞机上操作的机器人。在接下来的讲座中，我们将继续
and consider robots that operate only in the plane. And in the next lecture we are going
为三维内移动的机器人谈论这个问题。
to talk about this for robots that move within three dimensions.